In part one, Claude discovered six bugs,
two missing features, and a
documentation gap. Now, watch as Claude
fixes every single one of them, runs the
tests, and validates the results. This
is Vibe Coding part two.
Here's the fave icon repository on
GitHub.
Starting Claude code.
Now Claude wants to know if I trust the
files in this project folder.
Welcome back. Now I ask Claude to read
the to-do file from the part one video.
Claude asks permission to read the to-do
file.
Nine items total. Claude reads through
the entire list.
I tell Claude to start with the high
severity bugs first.
Cloud starts planning the bug fixes.
Cloud begins by reading the source
files.
46 Rust files to explore. This could
take a while.
It's building a mental map of the
codebase.
Searching for where colors are parsed in
the code.
Found the color module. Reading through
it now.
Still analyzing the color module. Start
a thought. I'm going to explain it.
Now Claude understands the issues and
plans to fix it.
Adding name color lookup table.
Continuing named colors implement.
Adding a lookup table for named colors.
Maroon, aqua, silver, gold, and more.
Updating module exports for new color
types.
Adding Unicode code point detection
logic.
Adding Unicode code point validation.
Adding tests and building project asked
owner.
Building and testing the changes.
Running cargo tests.
Compilation in progress.
Running cargo test.
Rest compilation.
Time for a coffee break.
Test running with CLI argument errors.
Code debugging. CLI argument errors.
Multiple bug tests complete.
Test results showing fixes work.
Running cargo clippy.
Cargo Clippy. Checking crates.
Clippy complete. Updating to-do list.
Test passed. I request checkpoint.
I request checkpoint and the medium
bugs.
Running tests. After checkpoint request,
running cargo format to clean up the
code.
Cargo lock health in the video alter
running format and clippy checks.
No clippy errors. Reviewing git diff.
Add named colors. Transparent support
and hex code points.
Commit complete.
Three bugs down.
Pushing the changes to GitHub.
Get push origin. Main.
The magic words.
Changes are live. Moving on to the next
book.
Now testing PNG.
File name output handling
cloud found that PNG files save as posig
tester ads
reading CLI argument handling code
adding wrench to the symbols file
also adding tool and hammer while we're
here
testing both file file name and wrench
symbol fixes.
Bug three, the PNG file name issue.
Running cargo tests on the codebase.
Running cargo format and clippy checks.
Bug three fixed.
All tests pass. No clippy errors.
I asked Claude to run the demo guide
first.
Claude is running through the demo
checklist.
Let's verify the demo O's work.
Running through the demo O checklist.
All demo those three set in passing
ready for checkpoint.
I noticed Claude didn't display visual
results.
I asked to see actual display output for
each demo.
I asked to clean up old demo outputs.
First
plot cleaning up old demo files before
running again.
Creating demo o directory and running
demo 01 fave icon.
Give me a one text fave icon files being
created and read.
Claw generating BM O2 unic code symbol
images.
Now the DEM O2 symbol images are being
created and verified.
Clone reading demo O2 image file sizes.
De O2 verified.
Starting demo 03
cold point demos.
Doom03
creating unic code point fave icon
images.
Doom 03 code point images created and
verified.
Goom04 creating custom color fave icon
images.
Goom06
creating animated GIF files.
creating the animated GIF.
Goooom07 listing available symbol
aliases.
Claude showing all dam who's passed with
bug fixes verified.
All bugs verified. I asked to see actual
visual output.
Thanks
much to hospitaling for sick scout.
I request visual demonstration of all
the demos.
Clode acknowledges and prepares to
display image Cloind at search letters.
Claude finding image viewer and opening
wrench o.
I clarify I want the display command
spec.
I clarify I want the image magic display
command.
I explain that display refers to the
image magic display tool.
Cloud switching to image magic display
command.
Wrench image now displaying via image
magic displaying.
Wrench fave icon displaying correctly in
image magic window.
Display command finished. Wrench icon
shown successfully.
We'll come back to this one.
Displaying the heart from hex code.
The red on black dim shows an empty red
square.
Something's wrong.
Let me investigate the red on black
issue.
Cloud discovers the X text is being
converted to the X symbol alias.
Cloud reads the text resolution code to
understand the bug.
Cloud identifies the bug and shows the
fix for text flag handling.
Building the fix, but there's a
compilation error.
After fixing the X icon now renders
correctly as liberal text
displaying the animated gear GIF.
The animation is too slow.
Ice scout speed settings.
Checking the help for frame delay
options.
Found it. Frame delay in milliseconds.
Trying delay 20.
Generating faster gear drift with 20 m
high.
Still too slow. Trying frame delay can.
Oh, how creation would be as I like to
talk not worrying.
Even delay 10 is too slow. Trying delay
one.
Still too slow with delay one. Something
is wrong.
Cloud tries more frames with minimal
delay.
I suggest the argument might be named
differently.
Cloud searches for how frame delay is
used in the code.
Searching through the codebase for frame
delay implementation.
Found it. GIF uses 10 seconds. Testing
with delay or
generating test GIF with 100C delay.
Classic units confusion happens to
everyone.
Cloud reads the GIFRunner source code
reading more GIF related source files.
Found the issue. Zero values default to
slow. Generating proper GIF.
Regenerating the Jeff with correct
timing.
Still no visible movement in the
display.
Checking the GIF file properties with
ident.
Still no visible movement.
The in girl looked online way graphites
on art direct beam
too fast now but discovered display
doesn't show animations properly
debucking animated gifs living the dream
maybe the browser will show it better
I ask for an HTML page to display the
GIF in browser
Cloud creates the demo HTML page and
opens it.
All the demos displayed together
podcasts along Kobany's estatic.
Custom color section looks great.
Custom color section looks great. Custom
colors section looks great.
Much easier to see everything at once.
I request slowing down the animations.
I notice the gear teeth appear
motionless due to rotation increment.
I explain that gear animation has a
rotation aliasing problem.
I describe how only the hub moves.
Not the tis
finish my feedback about the rotation
increment problem.
Gear is spinning. Star is spinning.
The animations work in the browser.
Browsers handle animated GIF files
natively so they display correctly.
Demo 06 verifes.
Much better than before.
The demos are working correctly. Now
I give instructions about the wrench
animation.
Still typing my instructions.
Still typing instruction.
Cloud running display commands.
Cloud executing display commands.
Code wasn't telling you what it cost for
existing
reading documented.
Showing documentation content.
showing rotation dems
still on wrench rotation.
I ask about the wrench animation.
Clode explaining static versus animated
images.
Clode explains I request a checkpoint.
I request a spinning wrench animation.
Adding the spinning wrench.
Making the demo o page more complete.
A wrench that spins. Peak fave icon
technology.
Demo page updated.
Star already added. I approve the
result.
Three animations now shown running
tests.
Running tests.
I ask about code points.
Get operations.
Get verification.
Get commit operation.
Get push.
Statista summary.
I request a demo o.
I ask about document.
I ask about font docs.
Clog checking at locks.
Code adding font docs.
Get commit push.
I ask about completion status.
Verification against to-do list.
Checking the final status table.
Showing feature census.
Status table eight of nine complete.
My name is partial and the college.
I request a help text update.
Editing help text.
Building and showing help.
Committing docs update. Showing help
text.
All items complete.
Cloud marks to-do items as complete.
All items complete. Feature
2 already complete.
I request a docs update.
Documentation.
The developer's least favorite task.
Almost done.
I ask about transparent or foreground
behavior.
Why can't the foreground be transparent?
I asked how hard it would be to add
guiding curs
updating docs.
Claude updating readme examples.
Claude checks the rendering code
looking for where foreground color is
applied.
Found the rendering logic.
Documentation command
cloud asks permission to implement
building the transparent foreground
feature.
Still editing code.
Start with both.
Still editing code in text. RS
build running.
Then testing.
Asking permission to display what?
Displaying the transparent foreground
result
shows solid red square
display failed. I'll put out the issue
running new test looked.
I caused a circuit
at least as large and narrow in town.
walks my feet. It's
I love temporary fig sort of thought.
Still updating docs shows error message.
Error message shows transparent at
ignite
supportingly.
Still implementing.
Still in the middle of implementation.
Verifying image transparency
running. Git hid
commit about desk and personal
shows
commit history.
Cloud asks about including the to-do
file.
Cloud types the commit command.
Committing to-do file hope it will
create conflication with close to
propulities.
Now where we got recently
is not supposed to be a bit
still committing locally.
shows GitHub after push.
Repository updated.
Done. All bugs fixed. Features added.
I asked Claude to run tests.
All six bugs fixed, plus new features
and updated docs. Check part one in the
description to see how Claude found
these issues. The fave icon tool is open
source on GitHub. Subscribe for more
vibe coding.
If you found this helpful, please like
and subscribe. Hit the bell for
notifications and leave a comment if you
have questions. See you in the next one.
Bye.