In Part 1, Claude discovered 6 bugs, 2 missing features, and a documentation gap.
Now watch as Claude fixes every single one of them, runs the tests, and validates the
results.
This is Vibe Coding, Part 2.
Here's the favicon repository on GitHub.
Starting Claude code.
Now Claude wants to know if I trust the files in this project folder.
Welcome back.
Now I ask Claude to read the todo file from the Part 1 video.
Claude asks permission to read the todo file.
Nine items total.
Claude reads through the entire list.
I tell Claude to start with the high severity bugs first.
Claude starts planning the bug fixes.
Claude begins by reading the source files.
Forty-six Rust files to explore.
This could take a while.
It's building a mental map of the codebase.
Searching for where colors are parsed in the code.
Found the color module.
Reading through it now.
Still analyzing the color module.
Sorry to thaw it, I'm going to explain it.
Now Claude understands the issues and plans the fixes.
Adding named color lookup table.
Continuing named colors implementation.
Adding a lookup table for named colors.
Maroon, aqua, silver, gold, and more.
Updating module exports for new color types.
Adding Unicode code point detection logic.
Adding Unicode code point validation.
Adding tests and building projects.
Asked Omar.
Building and testing the changes.
Running cargo tests.
Compilation in progress.
Rust compilation.
Time for a coffee break.
Tests running with CLI argument errors.
Claude dividing CLI argument errors.
Multiple bug tests complete.
Test results showing fixes work.
Running cargo Clippy.
Cargo Clippy checking crates.
Clippy complete.
Updating to-do list.
Test passed.
I request checkpoint.
I request checkpoint and the medium bugs.
Running tests after checkpoint request.
Running cargo format to clean up the code.
Cargo lock number half.
Running format and Clippy checks.
No Clippy errors.
Reviewing git diff.
Add named colors, transparent support, and hex code points.
Commit complete.
Three bugs down.
Pushing the changes to GitHub.
Git push origin main.
The magic words.
Things are live.
Moving on to the next book.
Now testing PNG.
File name output handling.
Claude found that PNG files save as .ico instead of .png.
Reading CLI argument handling code.
Adding wrench to the symbols file.
Also adding tool and hammer while we're here.
Testing both file name and wrench symbol fixes.
Bug 3, the PNG file name issue.
Running cargo tests on the code base.
Running cargo format and Clippy checks.
Bug 3 fixed.
All tests pass.
No Clippy errors.
I ask Claude to run the demo guide first.
Claude is running through the demo checklist.
Let's verify the demo's work.
Running through the demo checklist.
I notice Claude didn't display visual results.
I ask to see actual display output for each demo.
I ask to clean up old demo outputs first.
Claude cleaning up old demo files before running again.
Creating demo directory and running demo1 favicon.
demo1 text favicon files being created and read.
Claude generating demo2 Unicode symbol images.
Now the demo2 symbol images are being created and verified.
Claude reading demo2 image file sizes.
demo2 verified starting demo3 coldpoint demos.
Goom03 creating Unicode code point favicon images.
Goom03 code point images created and verified.
Goom04 creating custom color favicon images.
Goom06 creating animated GIF files.
Goom06 creating the animated GIF.
Goom07 listing available symbol aliases.
Claude showing all DOM who's passed with bug fixes verified.
All bugs verified, I ask to see actual visual output.
I point out Claude has not used display command yet.
I request visual demonstration of all the demo's.
Claude acknowledges and prepares to display image.
Not finding image viewer and opening wrenchdom O.
I clarify I want the display command specific.
I clarify I want the image magic display command.
I explain that display refers to the image magic display tool.
Claude switching to image magic display command.
Wrench image now displaying via image magic displaying.
Wrench favicon displaying correctly in image magic window.
Display command finished.
Wrench icon shown successfully.
We'll come back to this one.
Laying the heart from hex code.
They red on black dim all shows an empty red square.
Something's wrong.
Let me investigate the red on black issue.
Claude discovers the X text is being converted to the X symbol alias.
Claude reads the text resolution code to understand the bug.
Claude identifies the bug and shows the fix for text flag handling.
Building the fix, but there's a compilation error.
After fixing, the X icon now renders correctly as liberal text.
Now displaying the animated gear gif.
The animation is too slow.
I scout speed settings.
Checking the help for frame delay options.
Found it.
Frame delay in milliseconds trying delay 20.
Offering faster gear gif with 20 months prior.
Still too slow so trying a frame delay of 10.
Even delay 10 is too slow.
Trying delay 1.
Still too slow with delay 1.
Something is wrong.
Claude tries more frames with minimal delay.
I suggest the argument might be named differently.
Claude searches for how frame delay is used in the code.
Searching through the code base for frame delay implementation.
Found it.
Jif uses send seconds, testing with delay are off.
Generating CUS_JIF with 170 second delay.
Classic units confusion happens to everyone.
Claude reads the JIF runner source code.
Reading more JIF related source files.
Find the issue.
Zero values.
Default to slow.
Generating proper JIF.
Regenerating the JIF with correct timing.
Still no visible movement in the display.
Checking the JIF file properties with identity.
Still no visible movement.
Try different animation settings.
Too fast now but discovered display doesn't show animations properly.
Debugging animated GIFs.
Living the dream.
Maybe the browser will show it better.
I ask for an HTML page to display the JIF in browser.
Cloud creates the demo HTML page and opens it.
The most displayed custom colors section looks great.
Custom colors section looks great.
Much easier to see everything at once.
I request slowing down the animations.
I notice the gear teeth appear motionless due to the rotation increment.
I explain the gear animation has a rotation aliasing problem.
I describe how only the hub moves.
Not the tysmog.
I finish my feedback about the rotation increment problem.
Gear is spinning, star is spinning.
The animations work in the browser.
Users handle animated GIF files natively so they display correctly.
I say much better after animation fixes.
Much better than before.
The demos are working correctly now.
I give instructions about the wrench animation.
Still typing my instructions.
Still typing instructions.
Cloud running display commands.
Cloud executing display commands.
Cloud reading documented.
Showing documentation content.
Showing rotation demos.
Still on wrench rotation.
I ask about the wrench animation.
Cloud explaining static versus animated images.
Cloud explains I request a checkpoint.
I request a spinning wrench animation.
Adding the spinning wrench method.
Making the demo page more complete.
A wrench that spins peak fav icon technology.
Demo page updated.
Star already added.
I approve the result.
Three animations now shown running tests.
Running tests.
I ask about codepoints.
Get operations.
Get verification.
I thank you.
Get push.
Statistics summary.
I request a demo.
I ask about documentation.
I ask about font docs.
Log checking yetlocks.
Cloud adding font docs.
Get commit push.
I ask about completion status.
Verification against to-do list.
Adding the final status table.
Showing feature census.
Status table 8 of 9 complete.
My item is partial.
I request help text update.
Editing help text.
Editing and showing help.
Committing docs update.
Showing help text.
Online items complete.
Cloud marks to-do items as complete.
Feature 2 already complete.
I request a docs update.
Documentation.
The developer's least favorite task.
Almost done.
I ask about transparent or foreground behavior.
Why can't the foreground be transparent?
I ask how hard it would be to add.
Cloud updating docs.
Cloud updating read me examples.
Cloud checks the rendering code.
Looking for where foreground color is applied.
Found the rendering logic.
Contamination command.
Cloud asks permission to implement.
Building the transparent foreground feature.
Still editing code.
Start with both.
Still editing code in text.rs.
Go running, then testing.
Asking permission to display what.
Displaying the transparent foreground result.
Shows solid red square.
Display failed so I point out the issue.
We now run the new test.
Note that dash f transparent does not work.
Still updating docs.
Shows error message.
Dash f transparent causes an error.
Still implementing.
Still a little implementation.
I confirm and request a commit.
Verifying image transparency.
Running git addy.
Commit about see-through foreground.
Shows commit history.
Cloud asks about including the todo file.
Cloud types the commit command.
Submit the todo.
Wrapping up.
Shows github after push.
Repository updated.
Done.
All bugs fixed.
Features added.
I ask cloud to run tests.
All six bugs fixed plus new features and updated docs.
Check part one in the description to see how cloud found these issues.
The favicon tool is open source on github.
Subscribe for more vibe coding.
If you found this helpful, please like and subscribe.
Hit the bell for notifications and leave a comment if you have questions.
See you in the next one.
Bye.